# Francisco d'Albertas Gomes de Carvalho

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHE

International Institute for Sustainability (IIS). Estrada Dona Castorina, 124 Horto, Rio de Janeiro, Brasil 22460-320

1 + 55 11 99121 8851 | francisco.albertas@gmail.com | franciscodalbertas.netlify.app | franciscodalbertas | FdAlbertas

#### About me\_

Biologist with a master's and a PhD in Ecology with 10 years of experience working with applied research focusing on understanding how the spatial pattern of human-modified landscapes affects biodiversity, ecosystem services provision and the Climate. My main interests are related to landscape planning, spatial analysis, and the interface between science, policy, and impact evaluation.

### Skills

R - MARKDOWN - GIS - DATA ANALYSIS - ECOSYSTEM SERVICE MODELLING - ECOLOGICAL RESTORATION - WRITING AND COMMUNICATION - GOOGLE EARTH ENGINE - SPATIAL PRIORITIZATION

## Languages \_\_\_\_\_

PORTUGUESE (NATIVE) - ENGLISH (FLUENT) - FRENCH (ADVANCED) - SPANISH (INTERMEDIATE)

## Education

Universidade de São PauloSão Paulo, BrasilPHD IN ECOLOGY2017-2022

Universidade de São Paulo

MASTER IN ECOLOGY 2013-2015

Universidade de São Paulo
São Paulo, Brasil
BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES DEGREE
2006-2011

# Professional experience \_\_\_\_\_

#### **JOBS**

International Institute for Sustainability-IIS	Rio de Janeiro Brazil
international institute for Sustainability-115	RIO DE JOHEIRO BROZII

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER AND DATA SCIENTIST AT THE PROJECT TRADE, DEVELOPMENT AND THE ENVIRONMENT HUB 202.

Laboratório de Ecologia da Paisagem e Conservação-LEPaC(Departmento de Ecologia, Universidade de São Paulo)

Research Technician - Sao Paulo Research Foundation Training fellowship as part of the Biodiversity and

São Paulo, Brasil

ECOSYSTEM SERVICE SCENARIOS NETWORK (SCENNET)

Instituto Socioambiental - ISASão Paulo, BrasilJUNIOR ENVIRONMENTAL ANALYST (INTERNSHIP) - PROTECTED AREAS MONITORING PROGRAME2012-2013

Mineral Engenharia e Ambiente São Paulo, Brasil

JUNIOR ENVIRONMENTAL ANALYST (INTERNSHIP) - OIL AND MINING ENVIRONMENTAL IMPACT EVALUATION 2011-2012

#### **CONSULTANCY**

#### Aquaflora providing services to Vale S.A. São Paulo, Brazil

CONSULTANCY - EVALUATING THE BASELINE CONDITION OF PRIORITY ECOSYSTEM SERVICES AT WATERSHEDS POTENTIALLY
THREATENED BY MINING OPERATION IN MINAS GERAIS || STATE

World Wildlife Fund - WWF Brazil São Paulo, Brasil

CONSULTANCY - MONITORING DEFORESTATION AND FIRE WITHIN AMAZONIA AND CERRADO PROTECTED AREAS

2020-2021

#### Instituto Socioambiental - ISA

CONSULTANCY - MAPPING THREATS TO FEDERAL AND STATE PROTECTED AREAS IN BRAZIL

#### Klabin s/a Papel e Celulose

CONSULTANCY - PLANNING ECOLOGICAL CORRIDORS BETWEEN INDIGENOUS LANDS

Paraná, Brasil

2017-2018

São Paulo, Brasil

#### **Bloomberg Philanthropies e Global Road Safety**

CONSULTANCY - FLORISTIC INVENTORY OF URBAN AREAS IN SAO PAULO

São Paulo, Brasil

#### TEACHING

Fundação Getulio Vargas Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

PROFESSOR - CO-ORGANIZATION WITH CARLOS ALBERTO SCARAMUZZA OF A SHORT TERM COURSE ENTITLED LANDSCAPE USE, FOR MASTER IN MANAGEMENT STUDENTS

2022

## Research experience

#### **Conservation Science Group, University of Cambridge**

VISITING RESEARCHER SUPERVISED BY ANDREW BALMFORD

Cambridge, United Kingdom

# **Publications**

- d'Albertas, F., Ruggiero, P., Pinto, L. F. G., Sparovek, G., & Metzger, J. P. (2023). Agricultural certification as a complementary tool for environmental law compliance. Biological Conservation, 277, 109847. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biocon.2022.109847
- 2. González-Chaves, A. D., Carvalheiro, L. G., Piffer, P. R., d'Albertas, F., Giannini, T. C., Viana, B. F., & Metzger, J. P. (2023). Evidence of time-lag in the provision of ecosystem services by tropical regenerating forests to coffee yields. Environmental Research Letters, 18(2), 025002. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/acb161
- Pashkevich, M. D., d'Albertas, F., Aryawan, A. A. K., Buchori, D., Caliman, J.-P., Chaves, A. D. G., Hidayat, P., Kreft, H., Naim, M., Razafimahatratra, A., Turner, E. C., Zemp, D. C., & Luke, S. H. (2022). Nine actions to successfully restore tropical agroecosystems. Trends in Ecology & Evolution. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tree.2022.07.007
- 4. d'Albertas, F., González-Chaves, A., Borges-Matos, C., Zago de Almeida Paciello, V., Maron, M., & Metzger, J. P. (2021). Private reserves suffer from the same location biases of public protected areas. Biological Conservation, 261, 109283. https://doi.org/10.1016/j. biocon.2021.109283
- 5. d'Albertas, F., Costa, K., Romitelli, I., Barbosa, J. M., Vieira, S. A., & Metzger, J. P. (2018). Lack of evidence of edge age and additive edge effects on carbon stocks in a tropical forest. Forest Ecology and Management, 407, 57-65. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foreco. 2017.09.042
- 6. Acosta, A. L., d'Albertas, F., Leite, M. de S., Saraiva, A. M., & Metzger, J. P. W. (2018). Gaps and limitations in the use of restoration scenarios: A review. Restoration Ecology, 26(6), 1108-1119. https://doi.org/10.1111/rec.12882
- Metzger, J. P., Esler, K., Krug, C., Arias, M., Tambosi, L., Crouzeilles, R., Acosta, A. L., Brancalion, P. H., D'Albertas, F., Duarte, G. T., Garcia, L. C., Grytnes, J.-A., Hagen, D., Jardim, A. V. F., Kamiyama, C., Latawiec, A. E., Rodrigues, R. R., Ruggiero, P. G., Sparovek, G., ... Joly, C. (2017). Best practice for the use of scenarios for restoration planning. Current Opinion in Environmental Sustainability, 29, 14–25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cosust.2017.10.004